Finding aid for Interlochen Center for The Arts Records, 1927-2005
Bentley Historical Library
- Sound Recordings
  - Audio tapes
    - 1958
      - Dr. Joseph E. Maddy; the National Music Camp Story, 1958 July 04; 2 Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch (Box 84)
        - [Tape 2, Part 1], [851981-SR-11-1]; (Part 2; Dr. Joseph Maddy discusses his own life story and the musical camp's story.)
    - 1963
      - James B. Hause interview with Joe Maddy regarding history of Michigan School Band and Orchestra Association, 1963 May 05; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips (Box 84)
        - [Part 1], [851981-SR-15-1]; (Joe Maddy tape recording in reply to questions by James B. Hause regarding history of Michigan School Band and Orchestra Association.)
    - 1966
      - Maddy, WOOD-TV (Grand Rapids), the sound track of the documentary production about Maddy following his death., 1966 April; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch (Box 84)
        - [Part 1], [851981-SR-12-1]; ("Joe Maddy." Sound track from T.V. Show on Grand Rapids Station following Dr. Maddy's death.)
    - 1975
      - Interlochen, dedication ceremonies for Grand Traverse, Performing Arts Center, 1975; 2 Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch (Box 84)
        - [Tape 1, Part 1], [851981-SR-13-1]; (Part 1 of 2; Grand Traverse Performing Arts Center; Corson Auditorium; Dedication Ceremonies.)
        - [Tape 2, Part 1], [851981-SR-14-1]; (Part 2 of 2; Grand Traverse Performing Arts Center; Corson Auditorium; Dedication Ceremonies.)
    - 1977
      - Interlochen, WIAA, Public Broadcasting Corporation award for documentary (Box 84)
    - 1986
      - Wilson, speech to Historical Society of Traverse City on the history of Interlochen (Box 84)
    - 1991
      - Donald M. Currie's Retirement Party (Box 84)
    - 1992
      - Mozart at Lincoln Center, 2 audiocassettes (in a vinyl case) (Box 84)
    - 1993
      - IAA Orchestra performance at the National Concerto Competition at Interlochen (Box 84)
    - 1995-1996
      - Interviews conducted by Dean Boal
        - Paul Boylan, 2/1/1995 (Box 84)
        - Allen Britton, 2/2/1995; 2 tapes (Box 84)
        - Ed Downing, 1/11/1995 (Box 84)
        - Charles Eilber, 9/30/1995 (Box 84)
        - Frederick Fennell, 8/5/1996 (Box 84)
        - Gerie Greenspan, 1/20/1995 (Box 84)
        - Byron Hanson, 1/13/1995; 2 tapes (Box 84)
        - Karl Hass, 1/26/1996 (Box 84)
        - Howard Hintze, 1/30/1995 (Box 84)
        - Jack Hood, 8/5/1996 (Box 84)
        - Roger Jacobi, 7/24/1995; 2 tapes (Box 84)
        - Bob Murphy, 1/25/1995 (Box 84)
        - Jean Parsons, 1/27/1995 (Box 84)
        - Thom Paulson, 1/12/1995 (Box 84)
        - Ray Rideout, 1/19/1995 (Box 84)
        - David Stave, 1/17/1995 (Box 84)
  - Compact disc recordings
    - 1991
      - Joe Maddy's Interlochen (Box 84)
  - Vinyl disc recordings
    - Undated
      - Sixth string lesson, #1-2 (U.M. Broadcasting Service) (Box 80)
      - Sixth String lesson, #3-4 (U.M. Broadcasting Service (Box 80)
      - Band lesson (wind), #1-2 (U.M. Broadcasting Service) (Box 80)
      - Band lesson (wind), #3-4 (U.M. Broadcasting Service) (Box 80)
      - Singing lesson, U. of M. (Box 80)
      - University of Michigan Broadcast Service, unlabeled (Box 80)
      - Unlabeled (Box 80)
      - Male quartet, college songs (Box 80)
    - 1930s
      - National Music Camp concert, "Les Preludes," (Box 80)
    - 1934
      - 92nd Music Instructional Program (Box 80)
      - Class in Playing of Stringed Instruments (WJR) (Box 80)
      - Class in Elementary Singing (WJR) (Box 80)
    - 1935
      - Band and string (Presto label) (Box 80)
      - String (Presto label) (Box 80)
    - 1938
      - Music talent test, Wurlitzer (Box 80)
    - 1962
      - White House Concert, National Music Camp (Box 80)
    - 1964
      - Interlochen Youth Orchestra, Van Cliburn and Maddy conducting (Box 80)
    - 1967
      - "My Michigan" recording sent to Karl Haas (Box 80)
    - &, 1971; 1973
      - Interlochen, promotional records, 2 phonograph records (Box 80)
    - 1975
      - Concert for President Gerald Ford, High School Band and Chorus (Box 80)
    - 1977
      - National Music Camp, 50th Anniversary, recordings
        - World Youth Symphony #1 performing Hanson's "Romantic Symphony" and Liszt's "Les Preludes," (Box 80)
        - High School Symphonic Band #1, Revelli conducting (Box 80)
        - High School Symphonic Band #2, Wilson conducting including World Premiere performance of Hovhaness' Symphony No. 29 (Box 80)
      - National Music Camp, An Historical Montage of the First Fifty Years (Box 80)
- Scrapbooks, 1928-1979
  Fifty-one Scrapbooks (1928-1930, 1938-1940, and 1944-1978) help document the history of Interlochen and its leaders, especially Joseph Maddy. Arranged in rough chronology, they mainly contain newspaper and magazine articles, but a few include photos and manuscript items. Researchers will also want to make reference to the Printed Published Articles subseries, especially for the missing years. The scrapbooks offer a more comprehensive coverage of individual Campers and faculty, which should prove useful in documenting the growing importance of African-Americans on campus and other specialized projects. A detailed inventory of the Scrapbooks provides information on the contents of the individual volumes. The scrapbooks since 1978 have been retained by Interlochen.
  - National High School Orchestra and Camp, 1928-1930
    - April-August 1928 (Volume 1)
      (Mainly clippings; also some performance telegrams and photographs of the Camp under construction.)
    - Fall 1928-Fall 1930 (Volume 2)
      (Newspaper clippings; orchestra appearances in Washington D.C., and New York City are well covered.)
  - Joseph Maddy, 1938-1940
    - January-April, 1938 (Volume 3)
      (Largely activities of Music Educators National Conference, especially Maddy's presiding at its convention celebrating 100 years of music education in America and including newspapers articles, programs, photos, and some manuscripts (telegrams such as from Percy Grainger and interviews such as with Douglas Edwards).)
    - Fall 1939-summer1940 (Volume 4)
      (Largely Maddy's music education endeavors, especially his Southern trip in the spring of 1940 including clippings and photos.)
  - National Music Camp, 1939; 1941
    - July-September 1939 (Volume 35)
      (Clippings mainly pertaining to World's Fair concert conducted by Loren Maazel as well as to radio broadcasts.)
    - Summer 1941 (Volume 5)
      (Clippings, mainly on the movie about the Camp, "There's Magic in Music," and on the appearances of Frederick Stock and Paul Whiteman, including problems with Musicians Union head, James Petrillo, over the latter.)
  - Petrillo controversy, 1944
    - March and April 1944 (Volume 6)
      (Editorials about proposed Congressional legislation arranged alphabetically by state.)
  - National Music Camp, 1944-1966
    - Circa, April 1944-January 1945 (Volume 7)
      (Clippings only, including articles on the Petrillo controversy and on guest conductor, Percy Grainger.)
    - February-June 1945 (Volume 8)
      (Articles arranged alphabetically by state, including much on Petrtillo controversy.)
    - June-August, 1945 (Volume 36)
      (Clippings including much on Petrillo controversy.)
    - Circa, February-November 1946 (Volume 9)
      (Clippings arranged alphabetically by state, including hometown paper accounts of students at Camp as well as articles on the Petrillo controversy. This volume is in poor condition with the adhesive failing and many loose clippings.)
    - 1947, 1948 (Volume 10)
      (Each yearly portion contains clippings arranged alphabetically by state (and within Michigan, by city). The 1947 segment includes much on the Petrillo controversy, especially the Code of Ethics signed (September 24) by the Musicians Union with the Music Educators National Conference and the American Association of School Administrators.)
    - 1949 (Volume 11)
      (Contains issues of the Scherzo, Vol. 1, Nos. 1-8, at the front followed by clippings on the Camp arranged alphabetically by state.)
    - 1950, 1951 (Volume 12)
      (Each year begins with printed promotional items together with Scherzo issues and is followed by clippings arranged alphabetically by state (the 1951 portion concludes with Illinois). Issue No. 2 of the 1950 Scherzo mentions Norma Lee Browning's visit to the Camp.)
    - 1952, 1953 (Volume 13)
      (The 1952 portion contains selected articles covering July and August arranged with the out-of-state in front and Michigan (alphabetically by city) in back. The 1953 segment contains more articles and covers a longer time span (May-August), but lacks an ascertainable order: alphabetical by state, subject, or chronological.)
    - 1954-1956 (Volume 14)
      (The clippings in each yearly segment are organized in rough chronological fashion mainly from late June through August. The 1954 portion contains much on the threat to locate an air force base near Interlochen. One article also mentions Maddy's plan to winterize the Camp in order to make it a year-round institution. In 1955 the first European musicians came to study at the Camp, and because the legislature failed to appropriate funds, the taped Interlochen broadcasts were suspended. The following year, Maddy proposed a European tour by the Camp orchestra. The entire volume is in poor condition.)
    - 1958 (Volume 15)
      (Part I)
      (Clippings, circa March-November, covering Camp activities and personages. Much relates to the Musicians Union opposition to the Camp orchestra appearance at the Mackinac Bridge dedication. A folder of loose clippings can be found at the front.)
    - Part I and Part II, 1958-1959 (Volume 16)
      (The first portion is a continuation of the preceding volume, covering similar subjects and dates. The second, January-July 1959 includes much on the American Opera Workshop.)
    - 1959 (Volume 17)
      (Part II)
      (Wrapped scrapbook pages, circa January-early August 1959 (mainly May-July), continuing the coverage of the preceding volume.)
    - 1960 (Volume 18)
      (Coverage of the visits of Deems Taylor and Hugh Downs is included.
      (Wrapped scrapbook pages, mainly from June through August)
    - 1961 (Volume 19)
      (Folder of loose scrapbook pages contains clippings from June through August, including Van Cliburn's first appearance at the Camp. Because the adhesive is failing, it is in poor condition.)
    - 1962 (Volume 20)
      (Articles focusing on the appearance of Camp musicians at the White House. Many of the clippings are surrounded by small tabs indicating the names of the various newspapers in which they appeared. The adhesive is failing; so many tabs are loose or have fallen off.)
    - 1963 (Volume 21)
      (Newspaper articles, including on the "Today Show" broadcast from the Camp and plans for next year's International Youth Symphony. A subject index can be found at the front.)
    - 1964 (Volume 22)
      (Clippings including on Camp appearances by Van Cliburn and Luci Baines Johnson and on the International Youth Symphony. Again, there is a subject index in the front.)
    - 1965 (Volume 23)
      (Clippings in an apparently similar format to the preceding volume but without the index.)
    - 1966 (Volume 24)
      (Clippings which are organized chronologically at first and then, by subject (with insert papers bearing the descriptions).)
    - 1966 (Volume 25)
      (A continuation of the subject organization (with paper inserts) of the preceding volume. Mention is made of the start of Blue Lake Fine Arts Camp near Muskegon, Michigan.)
  - Interlochen Arts Academy, 1956-1966
    - 1956-1963 (Volume 26)
      (Articles about the efforts to establish the Academy and its first year of operation.)
    - 1963-1964 (Volume 27)
      (Clippings on the second year of the Academy's operation. A subject index is located at the front.)
    - 1964-1965 (Volume 28)
      (Clippings on the third year of the Academy. While an index is lacking, the format resembles that of the preceding volume.)
    - 1965-1966 (Volume 29)
      (Clippings covering the Academy from its opening in September through February .)
  - Joseph Maddy, 1966-1967
    - February-April 1966 (Volume 30)
      (Newspaper accounts of his statements on educating the gifted.)
    - 1966 (Volume 31)
      (Condolence telegrams, letters, and cards on his death, including from Hugh Downs, Karl Haas, Zoltan Kodaly, Eugene Ormandy, David Sarnoff, and George Romney.)
    - 1966-1967 (Volume 32)
      (Obituaries and memorials on Maddy's passing, mainly articles but also programs and a manuscript resolution passed by the Interlochen Board of Trustees.)
  - International Society of Music Educators, 1966
    - 1966 (Volume 33)
      (Newspaper and magazine articles and the program for the ISME convention held at Interlochen.)
  - Karl Haas, 1967
    - April-October 1967 (Volume 34)
      (Newspaper and magazine articles on the selection and inauguration of Karl Haas as President of Interlochen. An envelope of loose clippings is at the front.)
  - Interlochen: Camp and Academy, 1966-1978
    - August 1966-May 1969 (Volume 37)
      (Articles mainly of the Academy.)
    - August 1966-May 1970 (Volume 38)
      (Clippings on the Camp and Academy. The first two plus pages cover August-October 1966. The rest emphasizes February 1967-May 1970. There is no mention of Karl Haas' resignation.)
    - June 1967-September 1968 (Volume 39)
      (Mainly articles on the Camp, but also some on the Academy.)
    - July 1969-April 1971 (Volume 40)
      (Articles on both the Camp and Academy.)
    - May 1971-August 1972 (Volume 41)
      (Clippings organized in a roughly chronological fashion on both the Camp and Academy. It includes items on the ground breaking for the Grand Traverse Performing Arts Center.)
    - May-July 1972 (Volume 42)
      (Chronologically arranged articles mainly on the Camp. There are many loose clippings inserted at the end of the chronology, and many blank pages follow. Mention is made of the appointment of Paul Boylan as director of the Camp's University Division.)
    - November 1972-August 1973 (Volume 43)
      (Clippings on both the Camp and Academy which are arranged chronologically. They include items on the visit of Pablo Casals to the Camp in the summer of 1973.)
    - August 1973-February 1975 (Volume 44)
      (Chronologically organized clippings on both the Camp and Academy. Mention is made of the January 1975 death of Thor Johnson, early Camp conductor and Academy director.)
    - February-July 1975 (Volume 45)
      (Chronologically arranged articles on both the Camp and Academy. The include information on the dedication of Grand Traverse Performing Arts Center (Alden Dow, architect) in May and the visit of President and Mrs. Gerald Ford in July. Some of the pages are beginning to adhere.)
    - July-October 1975 (Volume 46)
      (Chronologically organized clippings on both the Camp and Academy. The first pages continue the coverage of President and Mrs. Ford's visit to the Camp. The pages of this volume are also beginning to adhere.)
    - October 1975-March 1976 (Volume 47)
      (The volume follows the chronologically arranged Camp/Academy format of the previous volumes. It includes an item (December 26, 1975) on Mike Wallace's early association with the Camp. Its pages are also starting to stick.)
    - March-April 1976 (Volume 48)
      (The volume continues the chronological Camp/Academy pattern of the preceding volume. It has many empty pages, and the filled ones are beginning to adhere.)
    - February 1976-May 1977 (Volume 49)
      (The volume follows the roughly chronological, Camp/Academy pattern. Some of the articles are starting to loosen from the pages. Mention is made (May 1977) of the state arts budget coming under attack.)
    - January 1977-August 1978 (Volume 50)
      (The volume offers a somewhat chronological coverage of articles about the Camp and Academy. It mainly deals with 1977 which is the fiftieth anniversary of the Camp. The same articles often appear in many papers, so small tabs containing the name of each paper are included. The pages are starting to adhere, and the tabs should begin to fall soon.)
    - August 1977-June 1978
      (The volume offers a somewhat chronological coverage with clippings about the Camp and Academy. Many continue the fiftieth anniversary publicity of the preceding volume. Again, numerous pages are beginning to adhere.)